# **Derrick Lannaman**

derricklannaman@gmail.com | github.com/derricklannaman

### **Full Stack Web Developer**

Hi, I'm Derrick. I have experience with Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Sass, Haml, relational databases, and Git/GitHub for source control. I have working knowledge Amazon AWS, TDD, plus an understanding of JSON and RESTful web services. I possess strong communication and interpersonal skills, Tech Startup experience, a demonstrated entrepreneurial spirit and the ability to work as a member of a team.

### **Professional experience**

#### memloom Inc.

March 2013 — March 2014

Part of core 3 person development team that took the Michigan-based technology startup from initial concepts and mockups to product launch. This role required translating founder and stakeholder requirements into buildable product feature sets and actively contributing ideas for product improvements. Technology stack includes - Rails, HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, CSS3, Facebook Integration, Postgres database, Heroku, Bootstrap, Git/GitHub. Used Jira for agile planning / project management.

# Ruby on Rails Training @ Thoughtbot

May 2013 - June 2013

Attended both Intro and Intermediate Ruby on Rails two-day training seminars taught by Thoughtbot in Boston, MA.

### Web Development Immersive Program @ General Assembly

October 2012 — December 2012

A rigorous, full-time training program that provides the technical and practical knowledge of full-stack web development. Core technologies include: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript & jQuery, AJAX, Git, Postgresql, Ruby and Ruby on Rails.

#### Other experience

- Team participant in the FinTech Hackathon (April 2013)
  - Stack: Rails, jQuery, Dwolla's api, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Heroku
- Working knowledge of *Adobe Fireworks, Gliffy*
- Project Management: JIRA & Pivotal Tracker

# **Entrepreneurial experience**

Texas Crazy Wings Inc. Owner/Operator

July 2007 — November 2009

# **BreedLove Salon** Co-Owner

May 2000 — Present

- Created and developed two businesses from concept to store opening.
- Oversaw the design, development and construction of Breedlove Salon LLC and Texas Crazy Wings, Inc.
- Possess effective management and leadership skills in managing a team of up to 12 staff members.
- Successfully operated Breedlove Salon for over 10 years.
- Created and established policy, procedures and operational standards for small business startup
- Responsible for personnel decisions relating to hiring, job training, payroll, and terminations
- In charge of product inventory, vendor management and daily operation of unit

#### **Education**

Adelphi University & Morehouse College

Attended in pursuit of a B.S. in Business Administration